Guide to the Peter Palmquist Collection of Humboldt County, California, Male Photographers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Materials, circa 1850-2003; Series II; 47.7; (145 boxes)
  - Photographic Materials
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - Prints from unidentified negatives (Box 113)
  - Photograph Albums
    This subseries consists of photograph albums and scrapbooks of various sizes. Each album is housed in an individual box.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by the surname of the photographer or the corporate name of the studio followed by material by unidentified photographers.
    - Christensen, Carl Mobius (Box 114)
    - Ericson, Augustus William (Box 115)
    - McGlaughlin, Robert Flint (Box 116, Box 117)
    - Young, Amos Millian (Box 118, Box 119, Box 120)
  - Oversize Photographic Materials
    This subseries consists of photographic materials created by or documenting individual photographers. Photographic material consists of vintage prints and copy photographs, and some associated publications and ephemera that possess dimensions greater than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.).
    - Arcata Union (Newspaper) (Box 121)
    - Baker, Ray Jerome (Box 121)
    - Bergeron and Gatliff (Box 121)
    - Colburn, Anthony Thomas (Box 121)
    - Cooke, Norman W. (Box 121)
    - Ericson Brothers (Box 122)
    - Ericson, Augustus William (Box 123)
    - Eureka Printing Company (Box BSD, folder 1)
    - Farrington, Thomas H. (Box 121)
    - Fassold, Peter (Box 121)
    - Flaglor, Amasa Plummer (Box 121)
    - Freeman Art Co. (Box 124)
    - Garrett, Edwin Orville (Box 125)
    - Gatliff and Thompson (Box 125)
    - Gatliff, Bertram (Box 125)
    - Gilchrist, Neil F. (Box 125)
    - Gilfillian, Adam W. (Box 125)
    - Grant, Martin Howe (Box 125)
    - Hadley, Gordon (Box 126)
    - Hagmann (Box 126)
    - Hakanson, Peter Erik (Box 126)
    - Holmes, Alexius Alexander (Box 126)
    - Hutchins, Vaughn G. (Box 126)
    - Keir, Walter (Box 126)
    - Kim, Suk Choo (Box 126)
    - Maseman, J. (Box 127)
    - Meiser, Jesse A. (Box 127)
    - Miller, George W. (Box 127)
    - Moulin Studio (Box 127)
    - O'Conner, Deming Lorin (Box 127)
    - Oliver, Mark (Box 127)
    - Petitpierre, Alain (Box 127)
    - Phegley, John W. (Box 127)
    - Seely Brothers (Box 127)
    - Seely Studio (Box BSD, folder 2)
    - Stevenson (Box 127)
    - Swanlund Studio (Box 127)
    - Swanlund, David Harper (Box 127)
    - Thompson, Joseph G. (Box 128)
    - Toms, James (Box 128)
    - Tracy, Joe (Box 128)
    - Vansant, Joshua P. (Box 128)
      - Studio sign (Box BSD, folder 3)
    - Wunderlich, Julius Prescott (Box 128)
    - Unidentified (Box 129)
  - Glass Negatives and Transparencies
    This subseries chiefly consists of glass plate negatives and transparencies produced by the dry collodion process created by or documenting individual photographers.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted Fragile Material in boxes 131-149 may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. These boxes contain fragile original glass negatives and transparencies.
    - Baker, Ray Jerome (Box 130)
    - Chase, Edwin S. (Box 130)
    - Ericson, Augustus William (Box 130)
    - Freeman Art Co. (Box 131)
    - Holmes, Alexius Alexander (Box 130)
    - McMillan Brothers (Box 130)
    - Outdoor World Publishing Company (Box 130)
    - Patterson, Frank (Box 132–136)
    - Seely Brothers (Box 137)
    - Swanlund Studio (Box 130)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      Glass negatives by unidentified photographers. Groups of negatives by discrete photographers are followed by negatives by photographers arranged by size.
      - Mansfield, Pennsylvania (Box 138)
      - United States Navy Ships (Box 139)
      - Ships and area in and around San Francisco Bay, California (Box 140)
      - 3 inches by 4 inches (Box 141)
      - 4 inches by 5 inches (Box 142)
      - 5 inches by 7 inches (Box 143, Box 144, Box 146)
      - 6 inches by 8 inches (Box 147)
      - 8 inches by 10 inches (Box 147)
  - Film Negatives
    This subseries chiefly consists of nitrate film negatives created by or documenting individual photographers. Nitrate film negatives are cellulose treated with sulfuric acid and potassium nitrate to create cellulose mononitrate, also known as commercially as Celluloid, a highly flammable plastic used in the first half of the twentieth century for photographic film.
    Restricted Fragile Material in boxes 148-160 may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. These boxes contain nitrate base film that is relatively unstable and a fire hazard.
    - Art-Ray Company (Box 148, Box 149, Box 153)
    - Baker, Ray Jerome (Box 154, Box 155, Box 156)
    - Patterson, Frank (Box 157)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - 4 inches by 5 inches (Box 158)
      - 5 inches by 7 inches (Box 159)
      - 8 inches by 10 inches (Box 160)
- Additions from Other Collections, Series II
  - Bound Volumes
    - Male Photographers of Humboldt County, California, Miscellaneous Notes, 1850-2000
      - Volume I, A-Baker (Box 161)
      - Volume II, Baldwin-Chaney (Box 162)
      - Volume III, Chappell-Davidson (Box 163)
      - Volume IV, Davis-Flaglor (Box 164)
      - Volume V, Flanders-Freeman (Box 165)
      - Volume VI, Freeman-Head (Box 166)
      - Volume VII, Hemenway-Kellogg (Box 167)
      - Volume VIII, Kennedy-McCune (Box 168)
      - Volume IX, McCurry-Meiser (Box 169)
      - Volume X, Meiser-Phegly (Box 170)
      - Volume XI, Phillips-Seely (Box 171)
      - Volume XII, Seely-Spesert (Box 172)
      - Volume XIII, Sprouse-Thieben (Box 173)
      - Volume XIV, Thompson-Vansant (Box 174)
      - Volume XV, Village-Zook's (Box 175)
    - Augustus William Ericson
      - Volume I, Chronology: 1848-1985 (Box 176)
      - Volume II, Miscellaneous Notes (Box 177)
      - Volume III, Personal Diary: 1871-1872 (Box 177Volume IV, The Swedish Collection)
      - Volume IV, The Swedish Collection (Box 178)
      - Volume V, The Swedes of Humboldt County, California (Box 179)
    - Fortuna (California) Color Slide Club, Miscellaneous Records, 1960-2000 (Box 180)
    - Humboldt County, California, Photography - Miscellaneous Notes and Lists (Box 181)
    - Inventory of Humboldt County, California, Photographs Transferred to Yale University (Box 181)
  - Biographical Files
    - Ackerman, Michael (Box 182)
    - Antón, Don (Box 182)
    - Forthuber, Don (Box 182)
    - Hakanson, Peter (Box 182)
    - Lufkin, Mark (Box 182)
    - Pierson, William (Box 182)
    - Swenson, Paul (Box 182)
  - Photographic Materials
    - Anderson, Hugh (Box 182)
    - Art-Ray Company
      - Photographic prints (Box 183)
      - Miniature photographic prints (Box 184)
    - Barber, W. B. (Box 182)
    - Blum, Robert Frederick (Box 182)
    - Cherry, Edgar (Box 182)
    - Eastman's Studio (Box 182)
    - Ericson, Augustus William (Box 182)
    - Eriksen, M. (Box 182)
    - Eureka Printing Company (Box 182)
    - Flaglor, Amasa Plummer (Box 182)
    - Freeman Art Co. (Box 182)
    - Freeman, Robert (Box 182)
    - Freese & Fetrow (Box 182)
    - Grant, Martin Howe (Box 182)
    - H. S. Crocker Co. (Box 182)
    - Harwood, Burhl L. (Box 182)
    - Hulbert, Neil K. (Box 182)
    - Keir, Walter (Box 182)
    - Mitchell, Edward H. (Box 182)
    - Meiser, Jesse A. (Box 182)
    - Pacific Novelty Co. (Box 182)
    - Patterson, Frank (Box 185)
      - Photographic prints (Box 185)
      - Photographic prints (Box 186)
    - Roberts, Mike (Box 182)
    - Stark, Alexander J. "Zan" (Box 182)
    - Swanlund, David H. (Box 182)
    - Swanlund, Oscar (Box 182)
    - Tuttle & Johnson (Box 182)
    - Vansant, Joshua P. (Box 182)
    - Wilson, Noah (Box 182)
    - Wunderlich, Julius Prescott (Box 182)
    - Weidner, Charles (Box 182)
    - Unidentified and various photographers by subject
      - American Indians (Box 182)
      - Arcata
      - Bucksport (Box 182)
      - Bunker Hill Ranch (Box 182)
      - Crescent City (Box 182)
      - Eel River (Box 182)
      - Eureka (Box 182)
      - Falk (Box 182)
      - Ferndale (Box 182)
      - Gibsonville (Box 182)
      - Grizzly Bluff (Box 182)
      - Humboldt, Alexander von (Box 182)
      - Humboldt Bay (Box 182)
      - Humboldt County Christmas week flood of 1955
        - Arcata Union (Box 187)
        - Greater Eureka Chamber of Commerce (Box 187)
        - Unidentified photographers (Box 187)
      - Humboldt County Christmas flood of 1964
        - Morris (Box 187)
        - United States Army Corps of Engineers (Box 187)
        - Unidenitfied photographers, 2 (Box 187)
      - Hydesville (Box 182)
      - Korbel (Box 182)
      - Logging (Box 182)
      - Lower Mattole Valley (Box 182)
      - Redwood forests (Box 182)
      - Samoa (Box 182)
      - Shively (Box 182)
      - Unidentified interiors, exteriors, and portraits (Box 182)
    - Clearwater, Bob (Box 182)
  - Oversize Photographic Materials
    - Baker, Ray Jerome, 1904-1909 (Box 188 (Broadside oversize))
    - Brown Photo Service, 1923 (Box 189 (Broadside oversize))
    - Bunnell, Schuyler Ulysses, 1915-1916 (Box 190 (Broadside oversize))
    - Ericson, Augustus William, undated (Box 191 (Broadside oversize))
      - Gilfillian, Adam W. (Box 193 (Oversize))
    - Freeman Art Co., 1918-1947 (Box 192 (Broadside oversize))
    - Keir, Walter, 1910-1918 (Box 194 (Broadside oversize))
    - Pacific Photo Co., 1912 (Box 195 (Broadside oversize))
    - Unidentified photographers
      - Eureka (Box 193 (Oversize))
      - Ferndale (Box 196 (Broadside))
  - Framed Photographic Materials
    - Ericson, Augustus William (Box 197)
    - Freeman Art Co. (Box 198 (Oversize))
    - Meiser, Jesse A. (Box 199)
    - Webster (Box 200 (Oversize))
  - Negatives
    - Art-Ray Company, Panoramic film negatives (Box 201)
    - Unidentified photographer, Glass negatives, 11 inches by 14 inches (Box 202)